I am I was taught meditation in a I
could describe how I was taught em so
involved being aware of sensations in
the body or focusing on sensations in
the body we talked about focusing in the
previous talk but and what's meant by
that sensation to the body's meant it's
it's basically you're supposed to focus
on what purely physical the physical
sensations is purely fit no mental no
imagination no visualizing just pure mental you're
no visualizing just pure mental you're
supposed to access the pure physical
pressure throbbing tingling whatever it
is whatever it is any body so that's the
first aspect to it and then the idea is
to not react to that so to not mentally
react to that and the idea was that what
the Buddha means of their own or your
reactions exactly I mean so so now you
do start so say that this the idea was
that this was what Sankara is what the
Buddha met mother was Sankara son Karan
is this mental reactions to the physical
sensations or physical what was going on
physically okay and so the idea is that
you don't react to those physical
sensations and if you don't react then
you're not creating some currents and
when you're not creating new some cara's
then reactions then old some cara's come
to the surface as physical sensations
that again you don't react to and if you
keep not reacting to this these this
then you're removing or getting rid of
or purifying an old stock of old react
adult Sankar how do you know that
because it all each other if you do it
for long enough you'll become
enlightened because you'll get rid of
all of your past stop of shankara's so
you can't know that now but if you keep
doing this at some points in the future
so to take you entranced yeah and not be
able to verify it yes because your only
way of relationship with your only
relationship because in a conceive your
only conceivable relationship with some
shankara's is to have body sensations
that's right which means they're
presently manifesting body sensations
they then you ascribe to be previous
pool of previous samskara is basically
somewhere in my unconscious yeah it's
it's somebody hit it that's right but I
know it's there because I'm perceiving
it now so then it's not unconscious now
all it's all you're not perceiving it I
think you I think the idea is how can
you have a thread that you can know that
you can be Cerner you can reflect upon
between something that's from
unconscious and something you're
conscious you can say I see the
connection between two because you would
be conscious of that it's not
unconscious yeah yeah so you can only
take it on trust and never ever be able
to verify that there are these
accumulated some cards the mysteriously
manages this body's sensations so that's
about baby exactly said but it provides
a story I mean that's basically what is
a nice psychological is donation look I
see all these things coming or going
it doesn't really require any kind of
you know existential type of ever do
know is out in anxiety or doubt or
listening to monitor these random
sensations have many my mind developed
like a fanciful pleasing story of
purification of energies yeah that's it
so so basically it provides you with the
motivation to keep doing this technique
because it's got a nice right right
right so we gotta go I understand why to
do this I'll just keep doing this
because that makes sense to me that
story so I'll so is that so I'll take
that on faith and I'll keep doing it
because in the future then I might have
this experience of all these probably
you have to start by dating things in
faith but the things you want to take on
faith are the things that you want to
then able to verify he didn't just replace
able to verify he didn't just replace
that faith with confidence he has the
suit to say yeah but this you can verify
no I cannot become conscious of the
unconscious yet sin Cara's before they
are manifested and then know them as
being there waiting to show himself on
the surface of your body just assumption
atop of assumption that was option that
you cannot even verify you're just
acting out of it because it pleases you
so that's one problem rather quark
fundamental problem yeah and also also
how can you how can you experience pure
physicality yeah that was the first
point yes actually yeah so that you
attempt with something purely physical
yes well you've ever attending to you
have no thought no thought of it you
want if he's purely physical means you
are not thinking it yeah how are you
talking about how is it manifest are you
knowing it how can you attend it yeah
attention is not physical yeah
act up your mind acts upon that which is
completely outside of its domain
physical anything anything appears is
somehow related to your mind of course
yeah that's why everything is a Dhamma
and that's where Tamas are basically the
objects yeah
after of the Faculty of the mind yes
here you are try accessing Buddhism yeah
area practicing Dhamma rooted in a
belief that you can't perceive Mattson
or mentally matter that is a few man
that's a pure experience of the matter
there is no thought or mind involved in
it whatsoever us from how is that even
conceivable except as a thought yeah
exactly so so so that's a little problem another
so so so that's a little problem another
problem obviously is how can you choose
to not react oh yeah there was a second
point that yeah well so there are these
things happening in my body these
sensations and I'm choosing to not react
upon them
yeah which is your current reaction
exactly yeah you might get better
reaction then very acting you could be
possibly restraining yourself but it's
still a reaction yeah so you developing
a belief that you're restraining a
particular type of reaction on account
of the action of restraint
that's not reaction well that's a wrong
view contradicts itself yeah so yeah you
contradicts itself yeah so yeah you
should restrain yourself if that's what
you're doing yeah but if you're
restraining yourself and holding a view
that restraining yourself is not the
action it's not the choice
it's completely beyond it means you look
look for that which surely is beyond it
that's why sense restrain itself cannot
result in a vitamin it's a good thing to
do but you cannot lighten you because as
you can see you can still hold and
develop even further wrong views on
account of it yes I all stop thinking
stop thinking that's a thought that you
have in your mind that claims to have
stopped thinking or they can stop
thinking by thinking that's why wrong
views abroad because they will at some
point at some level contains some
contradiction that's it
and then also you can say I think I mean
I don't see how any of this I've been
describing can help somebody to discern
the nature of your aggregates no because
I mean pop like so basically you've got
you're saying that you that's you attend
to pure matter by feeling it but every
not perceiver that but then your millon
when you're talking of the feeling
you're talking about pressure and
throbbing and sensual and so they're all
perceptions yeah so perception feeling
so you're basically confused and then
Sankara is manifest itself as matter but
this is your past intentions so your
past intentions manifest as material
which you feel it's all basically it's
all everything's all mushed together so
you can't how how its continuing to do
that gonna help you in also and also if
you're not able to verify the whole
thing of my paths and cars right now how
could have been the first person become
enlightened he couldn't have known that
I would say they said you can only know
it once you become a life and how do you
the first person to come along Tintin
he couldn't have taken that and Trust
because it was nobody to tell it hmm
so how do you became good it in what by
better if I think that you can verify
for your son and then instructing others
to do the same and if I tell you well
this is your fasting this is your
unconscious think means it's
non-existent yeah if it's unconscious
you're not conscious of it which is not
that I can't talk about it because so
you're talking about that means it's not
unconscious anymore you can talk about
it but once you do it cease to be that
which is in the unconscious because you
are consciously designating how's that
possible same when people say are the God the
same when people say are the God the
ultimate reality you can't express in
words you just expressed it there is its
expression why you can't put it in words
you just put it back in affable thing
yeah you only wish things would be that
easy
so I guess the question arises and if
sensation sorry if son Cara's and aren't
this pal stock of your previous
reactions and manifests on your body
physically that you should feel or
person or whatever until it all gets wet
away and all this stuff if that's the
wrong way of thinking about son Karan
then the question arises what did the
puddin mean when he talks it and so
Karan I think that sir yeah well it's
you know it's something that most people
[Music] teachers we're not necessarily develop
teachers we're not necessarily develop
its efficient enough it'll provide you
an explanation for it or use it to
describe anything basically ambiguous
did you know energies theories
thinking's patents or some kind of
cicadas if this is mystical entity as
basically if you need to overcome hmm
but literally the pali word Sankara
means what binding together keeping
things together I need you to give up
together for me Michael together they're
the making
it's basically something responsible for
things to be things in a way but not
that's the thing no pun intended
not not in a sense that it's it's some
sort of explanation of a universal
structure of your experience it's
something that pertains to the scent
itself and is the good a
self-extinguishing of Sagada pertains to
liberation of the other rather than
everything else so because they you know
it would be a tendency to think of
cicadas in the way the innovator was
thinking about it which is theoretically
true but practically not necessarily
adequate you want to see them from the
point of view of the self view from the
point of view of appropriation because
once you do that cicadas are gone okay
so what is then for somebody who is a
sense of self which means that sin
evitable has to be rooted in a sense of
ownership of things and now you have
somebody who isn't anymore he don't
where is it relinquished his sense of
ownership what's the difference it's
obviously noting things that are there
they were taking his mind and now not
taking his mind
those things that remain the same so
what's the difference then in saqqara
there it's basically whether it's taking
his mind or not his mind that's presence
of Saqqara means presence of taking
things is mine absence of Sankara means
absence of thinking is mine and it is
that very act of taking things as mine
that forms your sense of self and
formations or determines your sense of
self and determinations or the makers
the I making the my making you might not
want what every colonization was yeah
the point is without taking things is
mine you cannot be determining forming
maintaining the formation of your sense
of self so you stop taking things as
mine you stop fueling the sense if you
have to fade that's what I said about a
king the king wouldn't be a king without
his Kings possessions Kings ownerships
that make him a king he's not a king so
he feel yourself maintain things that
make you yourself that's why you are
responsible for your own self view and
that's what cigar is
if you look at that menu both of your
sensations not already don't already
you're already dismissing it you want to
look whether buddy sensor somewhere
where where is my own sense of self
where is my own sense of ownership where
are the things that are dear to me
where are the things that then sort of I
find pleasing I would be emotionally
disturbed if I were to lose that's where
you look for sin Cara's maybe like my
mom meditation technique well once you
add some time and they can become a
touchy subject yeah but again yeah
basically whenever there is a basis for
suffering means there is the
appropriation there are cicadas yeah
there are determinations they determine
you as a sensor self but if you can you
know I mean maybe this is no more
Talavera saying you can talk about Sun
Cara's in a more general sense yes let's
talk about a particular type you know
car but why are we talking about it in
the first place because we all want to
be free things I want to be other so you
don't talk about them in any other sense
okay unless you're free like it's not
incorrect to say did some cars of
determination of the five objects as I
know Vera did but it's inaccurate
practically because now somebody will
read that and think oh I understood
what's and Carozza
what he's still a / - Gina but wouldn't
it be helpful for a lot of people to
think that determinations of some car or
whatever gonna call it if they have
absolutely no other reference to do with
what things mean it's not to do with
things that appear in your body is to do
of course with the meaning of what I'm
saying now is that if you have no other
reference for as to what cicadas are
when you're gonna describe it's better
but now that you can have a more
accurate reference the one I'm showing
you yes this is redundant I say okay so I
yes this is redundant I say okay so I
thought it's not helpful then yeah so
that's the whole point where did the
things that I own why do I own them
because you don't realize you can own
them hence ignorance determines the sense of
hence ignorance determines the sense of
ownership yeah of each of our chests and
convient that's it is the most practical
thing you can have it's nothing abstract
unless of course you have no idea what
it is in case it's everything extra yes
and it's certainly not observation of
the tingling in
what difference does it make so you can
observe what you want and try to manage
and sort of tailor your responses and
your behavior to what I was happening
fundamentally you're fully appropriate
in the body as a whole so you can you
can dismiss the legs you can dismiss
everything but overall it's still my
body so really I'm only trying to avoid
the parts by ignoring the whole yeah
deal with the part by ignoring the
ownership of the whole certified what's
Ankara's Oh begin by looking for
something which is day to you something
else you carry on something which is you
have to start on the emotional basis and
then see what that emotional basis
depends upon and then look in the
characteristics of that as we describe
the niches inaudible that's what the car
is up hence you understand what cicadas
are you're not ignorant of them between
there are no sand car as they determine
you as you anymore yeah because it
requires you to not know that to
maintain them so yeah by all means
abandon all sin Cara's not through your
like mechanical management's was a
psychological sort of meditation
technique but by understanding what they
are and your understanding you will
understand what they are if you look
where they are and they are where your
sense of ownership is determinations
formations order and it's always it's
always a background phenomenon of course
so people going oh this these son cows
in my knees my knees could that me be
your knee if you already distinguish the
ownership of the entire body as a whole
if you fully understood what this body
is like liable to all these elements
we'll go back to that it can't be used
to begin with this body cannot be yours
even if you wanted to the only way to
maintain yours is to you know the fact
that you can be yours and people you
know that fact when they refuse to think
about death they refuse to think about
sickness aging losing the loved ones and
so on that's how you ignore us the
father and you ignore it because example
and you ignore it because example
doesn't think about it so when you start
with a sense of ownership thinking about
how you cannot own things that are dear
to you is very unpleasant and that's
what people don't do it as simple as
that so would you then if you don't if you do
so would you then if you don't if you do
start reflecting like that and you
genuinely develop complete this passion
towards your own body and what happens
to it
would you still be concerned about the
random tingling sensation in my knee no
because I already abandoned the whole
domain what difference is in it and then
you wouldn't also be concerned from like
agreeable things that happen to agree
with food agreeable sounds so
disagreeable sounds wouldn't bother you
either could you have abandoned the
whole domain of the body and you won't
abandon the domain of the body the
nature of the body by staring and its
particular parts because you're losing
because of the well you want the force
the determination did the act of staring
and this you are then willingly
excluding the whole picture you can't do
it Bobby exactly and you can only
discern what is meant by body when the
Buddha talks about body yeah by looking
at experience is a whole but like you
can't eat when you're focusing in on
something you're actually turning away
from anything today and that's when
people think oh well no you develop the
focusing first and then you look no
because when you look back you were
looking the same manner in front of me
overly attending focusing on it which
means what you're gonna see it's not
gonna be the background of your
attention the background of your seeing
because you own you own the only thing
you know to do is attend attend those
folks focus okay now a focus on that
which is behind my focusing well now
that's your focus and something else is
behind and you have no needs of
discerning it cuz all you know is how to
stay lit what you focused on that's a
really seeing some Cara's means learning
how to an allow the background to be
neither yes to tell a lot about if there
was a way you know more be the more more
indirect sense it's it's it's allowing
like giving a sense of ownership to
manifest yeah
so that you can see its basis as unabled
if you see mean permanent of some Cara's
as in an owner ability of that which is
yours yes you
cannot remain mine on like I'm not in
charge of this I'm not in control you
cannot maintain that about any further
debt so that's that's the point here
because if you think you sort of ah
there is no self I wouldn't be dealt
with that simply by denying it now I
just need to look at these mysterious
manifestations from my unconscious pool
of consciousness through these some
cards and somehow in the course of time
purify myself through these
observational techniques well your
starting point there is to stop denying
oh yeah and to recognize that there are
still things that are dear to you the
you and also dress in your hoping there
by doing such and such technique you
will magically address all the things
that you are still liable to know the
only way to address things you're liable
to is to go face to face we think you
are there is no skillful means or any
kind of sort of a carryover I'll do this
and it will magically free me from that
the only way to free yourself from
things you are subjected to things
you're burdened by is to stop as now the
time that I have a little burden yeah
well which you can only do if your
knowledge about theories I am very sense
of ownership star by star there now
within that I need to find basically I
need to learn how to regarding these
things is not mine
no 3d9 not to try to get rid of it no
sir but understanding that they're not
mine cuz they come to mind because they
are truly not yours they cannot be yeah
and that's why liberation is possible in
the first place and so that can only be
found through the things like not yours
yeah yeah yeah since it's not a when
people think like how ownership is a
problem so I'll throw away my
possessions oh you were about simplistic
you know you shouldn't own things you
don't need to own things already to be a
subject to ownership because you already
own your body your senses your your
senses you own anything that can come to
your senses so if you think they're
throwing away things will feel from
ownership means you you're making
yourself even more deluded
the nature of ownership which is on the
level of the senses on the level of the
body on the level of this and QALYs but
if you remove the ownership from their
level through fully understanding how an
honorable those things are and by their
I mean impermanent by that I mean a
nature then everyone as the Buddha said
he himself can stay in the King's
palaces each to two bowls of food and
whatnot and not own anything not be
attached to anything cause he abandoned
the whole domain with these things to
manifest he's freed from circars
I worship is allowable yeah it's not the
I said before it's not the things that
exactly yeah
so understanding itself is determined
self-determination sure what is
determined by your effort to understand
that's what the Buddha said is I will be
asking is nirvana and determined what
it's undetermined as a phenomenon but in
a way it's determined and he said the
body is determined by the practice of a
holy life so your understanding if you
reach it is determined by all the
previous effort to understand so in that
sense is determined and those
determinations cannot beyond me you say
this self is determined by seeing itself
is determined here self isn't it it was
an understanding so oh yeah to
understand itself is determined that's
determined latest understandings
incarnate that's a car religion you're
supposed to understand that the self is
determined yeah sure that's not mean sin
Cara's up to the only understood
correctly first if you accept your sense
of self and the ownership things that
are dear to you cicadas are not
understood in a sense of look this tree
is impermanent and each unknown above
all this and Cara's will come to pass I
don't care about that yes concerning
yourself yeah so it needs to start with
a personal concern and then through that
concern you can get to the stand from
saying that even an understanding in a
way it's also determined by your efforts
to understand and that experience it
cannot be taken his mind
it cannot be appropriated that's why I
said Nirvana is awesome cata it's not
determined by the determination of
ownership but it is development for your
previous efforts to develop it and
practice it but now that's done that's
why it's irreversible but as so starting
out when you read all sin Cara's of
Legion mmm-hmm means anything so that's
what they all self determination
everything that determines your senses
yes yes yes yes so the plurality of sin
Cara's it's true the singularity of the
sense of self that's
how you can only see it rightfully it's
not like that Superman Superman that's
about it
thus I am NOT my own no I am myself then
I the video bothered I can't be my own
because I'm not my own mas as in I'm not
in control of my own life my sense is
that it so within that sense of I am you
then find all these other things that
could be determining you that are
determining it and you realize they are
controllable and the reason they are
unknowable is because they're plural hmm
like the singular mastery the sense of
yourself master is always singular it
was like self-determination yeah no
that's that's important fun because
people would even this what we're
speaking we probably could understand is
our case you just find these random
things and then sort of reflect how they
cannot be yours that's accurate in
theory but in practice you want to do
that through your sense of self not left
right up or down before or after what is
determining this thing exactly so first
you have to kind of start in the reverse
order the right order so I am I am such
and such I am such and such in such a
such situation now there is obviously
some emotional engagement because there
has to be something felt and that's the
basis through which you start looking at
things that idea to you that's why I
like mindfulness of death done rightly
will up to then everything cuz it
potentially also fundamental
appropriation of your experience as a
whole was the body senses all of that
that said that you know those
determinations that are always seen in
in relation to this sense of self so
it's always a kind of those things will
be seen as determinations that only
through the services so and that's
exactly what the termination is exact
the negative yeah and that's why that's
what people get confused that's why the
Buddha himself said when he described
various aggregates he said this is what
matter is this is a feeling is this what
perception is determinations and
consciousness then what is matter this
is
what is the terminations and then list
the ferrets since that which they say
yes everything can be a determination if
your sense of self depends on it which
means in order to see it as a
determination you need to see it through
your sense of self not like oh yes look
out there
let's see permanency in the context
where you are so the context is self
yeah it is this is the context we're
going on stuff yeah is my cell so even
if you look at the same thing but if you
don't look at it through the sense of
self to the right content you want the
right context you are not seeing it as a
determination because it isn't seven
again it isn't determining is that the
self because the termination is more of
a relationship yeah or between your
sense of self and things that make you
sense a self sense of self respective
yeah direction of perspective yeah but
that pertains to because that's the song
problem CNET context of self is
determined by the content that I'm
taking yes pertain to me my that under
that scene it undermines the ignorance
of their situation yes which is a sign
in that order
no because sense of self depends upon
certain contents you can say this is
mine this is my definition is in my
belongings all these things but okay so
now you read that okay so now you go and
look at individual the crown the cape
the throne all these things but now
they're they are the things that are
determination for him and even if you
are king yourself they are determining
you but the only way to see them is
determination is first to see them
through your king hood so to speak
through your sense of self what you are
and then see how this sense of self is
present enduring simultaneously is now
in the right order determined by these
things at the same time so it's not
determined by you choose it to be King
is determined by you choosing to own
these things that who can be taken away
sir your country that's your sense of
I'm King can also what cannot remain
standing so the only way to see determinations
so the only way to see determinations
to see them through that context and if
people forget that it would be like okay
I'm a king
oh and now I start examining your crown
you did all this cigar is in focus of it
this is a permanent focus focus look at
what it's made of to prove that the
whole is impermanent and all these
things and never ever for a single
second do things in the right order
whereby first you start I am a king
dad's determined by this not I am a king
that has all of this because that's like
I am this is mine
it's other way around I am because there
are things that are mine through that
sense of I am young I am a king and now
I get mine and now I go to the next so
that's why I keep probably that's
probably the patina with this is who I
am and then that's why I'm given these
things Rob there was so the opportunity
for as long as they don't have prude
that view realising that whenever we do
a point operations whenever we do a
contemplation or like when we recorded
things it's always like I keep insisting
on being aware of your situation and
then while you're aware of situation you
look at other things within that because
it's doing exactly the same principle so
while I am a king there are all these
things that I own because of which I'm a
king while I am a king right here right
now so while I'm hanging King right here
right now what if I were to lose my
castle today I would not be a king
anymore vial of a king right now that's
how you will also be unable to remain
indifferent to your ownership or loss of
ownership the only true way to be
indifferent towards it is to abandon any
sense of ownership through that sense of
self it's been generated by that
ownership but if you start looking for
ownership and abandoning ownership like
I'm doing the sin Cara's about not not
through the sense of self but as an
afterthought as a management technique
as a meditation technique as a magical
hope they will happen at the end of it
your sense of self remains unaffected
which means you'll be owning bad now and
that's exactly why people would get
upset and you basically know somebody
yeah disagrees even on the level access
you is wrong you get upset even if I'm wrong
is wrong you get upset even if I'm wrong
in saying that you are wrong if you're
getting upset
that's a probe that should be a problem
for you red flag if you come across
someone else's views and you get upset
on account of them don't you tell you a
lot and that's a work for you to do
instead if you truly understood you will
be able to see wrong fuses wrong using
right users reviews so if somebody comes
and says you are wrong you will be able
to see by the day wrong in saying that
or whether they're right is saying that
in which case you'll be more than happy
to upgrade your behavior but it needs to
be taken on that personal level which is
initially unpleasant and that's why
everybody refuses it that's why we just
discussed that before how the most
rational people would abandon the whole
intellect if if something folks triggers
the feelings that's it it's something
unpleasant that's it but it's unpleasant
to to accept it's unpleasant it's a
pleasant for me as a king to think how
I'm a king no because I'm a king yeah
but because I have all these things that
define me as a king now I can think
about those things as an afterthought
when I don't really think through the
feeling book but being threatened as a
king no I just think it may be pondered
on the days when I have energy and
that's usually how most people practice
the Dhamma
or think about impermanence and stuff
when I'm something particular to deal
with or like you know when I feel like
it but no needs to be done on that
that's why I like it essentially I'm
prey to suffering as the world is crowd
means you're always on the verge of
anxiety recognizing that yeah all this
can be uprooted in a finger snap and you
cannot even conceive how to crack it so
if that's your context you would be
seeing everything else that's kind of
going against it which is any form of
ownership any form of lost passion anger
distraction carelessness it's again step
context that's why it's I'm also
against it context yeah of things beat
your self-pity term yeah exactly it's
maintaining the wrong context of I am
without things I mind because I know you
are because you think you taking things
to be yours and that's where that right
order of things if you'll be looking at
the same thing you will be completely
wrong thing if you don't see through the
right order the three women people in
the suitors would understand the poor
the first time you'll be like wow it's
like putting that which was second
putting it first and put him first way
to a second he was it's all bare like
there's nothing you can be introduced
but oh but I thought okay okay so it's
like what I thought was upside down I'm
covering what was covered but right
there that's it so you want to see some
cards you have to see them on the right
level because otherwise you'd be just
looking as Dahmer's yeah at random
phenomena yeah attending to it focusing
and ascribing in values and significance
that he doesn't have because you're not
seeing your driveway
so you girls have to say that
Oh st. car is our dukkha yeah all all
snaps Olsen Carter's are honorable did
also comes a dukkha because they are
honorable so because all things true
your sense of self Teddy tell me
innocence itself cannot you cannot be
their master they are aren't honorable
because of that you can own them
you took the ownership given to you for
granted but they don't the fact that
ownership was given to you means you
can't own it because it can be taken
away like a borrowed go borrow jewelry
double to say so because all these
cicadas through my sense of self cannot
be owned that's why they cannot be like
a basis for lasting satisfaction for
pleasure that's why they are suffering
that's why they are unpleasant because
of that this sense of self is thus up
not hmm it's not like the conclusion so
see that this sensitive information
determine it by these things yes that
sense of self is that automatically not
felt as mind of it cuz it's the thing
which is not mine
yeah all Dahmer's that's I keep saying
like if you see if you see on each and
dukkha correctly you don't then have to
go and figure out an otter see I
Nietzsche Duga correctly means seeing a
niche and uka through your sense of self
which then means seeing a Nietzsche
dukkha this sends herself through which
I'm seeing this cannot be mine so you'll
experience the whole is experience of
Hinata but even seeing impermanence and
but even seeing impermanence and
suffering as being bound up with each
other and inseparable I think a lot of
people think see though there yeah they
see the things that kind of it's not
it's not that's like you saying it's
unknowable if you wanna say the I did
you say the knee is serious this is
stated flux is nothing quite pleasant
sure what would people say look the more
the science has proven everything is
impermanent yeah that's not what impermanence is
yeah that's not what impermanence is
impermanence is unknown ability modern
science cannot prove that
which can only be felt a house on the
level of ownership of non ownership yeah
so I can say look this isn't permanent
this isn't permanent this isn't
permanent this isn't permanent
everything is impermanent but that's
still it's not seen as impermanent
things that determine me right here
right now is just seen in relation to me
right here right now that's something I
am and all these things that can't be
mine are not mine but I still am
basically so in order to see a Nietzsche
and dukkha correctly in order to see
Sankara correctly needs to be seen
through the sense of self so in order to
see our own ability correctly you need
to see it through the sensor one has to
be a threat
yeah through this to the ownership and
it's a threat if it's seen as that
ownership depends opponent not village
cousin so it has to pay that out threat
to where you're beginning you know as I
said it's a threat if it's seen that
your ownership depends upon it not
merely relates to it externally yes
because usually that's how people
observe any just like external
relationship and then I infer that us I
am in permanent but that's it I am I
don't question that
in permanent so you just kind of coat
another set of belief on top of your
unquestioned sense of I am and implicit
ownership of things and saying you want
to see dukkha correctly you have to see
through your sense of through the
pleasure ability of you sent yourself
off your sense of ownership office sense
of I am to the safety of your sense of I
am that's how you see the threat not
like safety threat is over there that's
not the threat saying it you want to be
to see that there's you to be has a
knowledge of another hmm
you have to go through that anxiety
existential an unraveling or game you
are going to die yeah you know you've
got no basis your basis you're
determined yourself is pretty talking
about things which are not again the
center spoke about it so many times
okay you're not gonna feel good about it
yeah you're going to feel it dukkha
you're gonna feel the way sign
significance of your having to do that
but I think once you feel this so you're
wrong yeah this is everyone familiar when you
yeah this is everyone familiar when you
start to see things correctly no that's
the whole point I mean the suit to say
like the normal search will come out
once you recognize there are only two
outcomes of fully recognizing the nature
suffering correctly is Monticello
mindful of the pottery leads to mental
derangement or search noble search so
once you face that extension anxiety you
would like to lose your mind or if you
compose well develop your virtue
beforehand have sense of restraint they
will control your behavior they will
then make you go mad if you she do it so
if you developed in terms of your
behavior you won't go mad but it doesn't
mean you won't feel the weight of that
anxiety and that so it says two outcomes
mental derangement or noble search in
other words you can't remain indifferent
you can't go back to your life you know
before because you've already undone a
great deal of ignorance by becoming
aware of anxiety that's why I keep
saying is that is not a problem it's a
symptom basically it's a beginning of
recognition of what your existence is I
indicate you yeah actual yeah straight
zhenya I what I was just saying that
your mindfulness of the body leads to
great existential dread mmm-hmm who says
that less hungry trendek I am still all those
less hungry trendek I am still all those
things about that mindfulness the body
know the benefits of I plus the body in
the first one is no but no that's
exactly where same yeah that's a good
thing yeah it's a good thing it's a
necessary basis if I'm prayed to
suffering young man thinks that and then
because of that goes to the whole world
wants to practice wants to commit his
life to the desing not to the lofty
serving of the Dharma society but to
actually become another hundred freedom
so practice it how would you feel if you
were pray if you're being hunted by
everything and nothing will be very
anxious existence day they are so yet
it's unpleasant what's the first
attitude towards this pleasure I will
get rid of it okay so now you know
that's not what you should be acting out
of stop trying to get
so that would then force you to start to
learn how to see through it but yeah if
you get an Italian oh no that's wrong
don't even go there just just watch your
nostrils feel the soles of your feet
stop thinking stop thinking too much
thinking just stop thinking you mean
when you feel bliss that's it that's it
you think that will free you from your
from the essential suffering and
everything else and that's why the
butter satipatthana a number of places
talks about the difference between
feeling like so yeah you got unpleasant
thing the pleasant feeling but you got
feeling of the flesh mmm and I'll miss a
feeling that's not of the flesh near
your innocence so and that needs that
needs to be distinguished you need to
gonna recognize okay this is unpleasant
but it isn't sensual it isn't anything
to do the senses this unpleasant thing
so there's the danger in it exactly
it's only an essential danger a danger
essential domain yeah